# FRONT END DEVELOPER

### SUMMARY

My name is Caleb Matteis, I'm a front-end developer with experience working with full stack applications and websites. I'm in the process of completing Springboard's immersive bootcamp were I'm learning languages such as Javascript, Python and the front end framework React.

### SKILLS

FRONT END: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, JQuery, AJAX, Axios, React, Bulma, Sass

BACK END: Flask(Python), Express(JavaScript/NodeJS)
BACK END: Flask(Python), Express(JavaScript/NodeJS)
DATABASE: PostgreSQL, SQL-Alchemy(ORM), MongoDB

**TESTING:** React Testing Library, Jest(server-side JavaScript), Unittest(server-side Python) **OTHER:** Restful API development, Git/Github, OOP, test-driven development, responsive design

LANGUAGES: Python, Javascript

# **PROJECTS**

Weather Me Nov. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- The goal of this project was to use a third-party api to collect data, then use data to build a full stack application.
- The tools I used were Python and Flask to build the backend, PostgreSQL for the Database, and open weather api for weather data.
- For the front end I used Html, CSS and the CSS framework Bulma.

Personal Portfolio Site Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- Built a personal portfolio site using Html, Css, and Sass
- Purpose of this site is to showcase my ongoing development as Software Developer.
- The site is also responsive and designed to be mobile compatible

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Springboard**, Software Engineering Fellow, San Francisco

May 2020 - Current

- Collaborated with Senior Software Engineers on projects weekly
- Developed skills in database, and unit testing
- Bulit in-depth capstone projects covering front-end web development, back-end web development, and full stack development.

United States Postal Service, City Mail Processor, Morristown, Nj

Oct. 2013 - Current

- Managed a route that averaged 16 complaints a week prior to my assignment, and brought it down to 3 complaints every three months.
- As office safety capitan I was able to implement strategies to reduce in office accidents from 10 in 2019 to 0 in 2020
- Transitioned a 300 hundred unit apartment complex from door to door delivery into closter box delivery. This helped to increase mail accuracy by 70%.

# **EDUCATION**

Springboard Spring 2020 - Current

Certification Software Engineering Track 2021

800+ hour hands-on curriculum with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 portfolio projects covering front-end web development, back-end web development, and full stack development. Mastering Javascript, DOM Manipulation, Git, Ajax, jQuery, Python, Flask, SQL, PostgresQL, Node, Express, React, and Redux.

### VOLUNTEERING